Joe Nyland

59 Harper Close, Winnington, Northwich, Cheshire, CW8 4SU Tel: 07568 541556

Email: work@joenyland.me
Web: joenyland.me
DOB: 24 September 1990

Skills

- 3 years professional experience in as a full stack developer and DevOps engineer using the following technologies:
 - Ruby, Rails, PHP, Python
 - · HTML, CSS and JavaScript
 - Puppet
 - Apache and Nginx web servers
 - MvSOL
- Works extensively with Amazon AWS cloud services on a daily basis, utilising their extensive APIs
 to manage and provision services. Also experienced configuring and working with VMware
 ESX/ESXi and Microsoft Hyper-V virtualisation technologies.
- Experience working with Google Webmaster Tools, Analytics and Adwords and their respective APIs in SEO marketing campaigns.
- Has designed, built and optimised and now currently hosts and maintains small websites and web apps for local SMBs.

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer & Full Stack Web Developer, Formisimo, August 2014 - Present

- Maintaining a SaaS checkout and form analytics service: Formisimo. Clients include: Secret Escapes, Barcelona FC, Travelex, and Financial Times.
- Architecting, building and maintaining Nudgr: A real time machine learning based exit intent product. Nudgr uses automatic machine learning to improve the conversion rate of client's online forms and checkouts. From data modelling to algorithm optimisation through to implementing algorithms in place in the Nudgr real time prediction service. Clients include: Very, William Hill, Cornerstone, Secret Escapes, and Financial Times.
- Developing, refactoring and supporting PHP and Ruby backend code.
- Building, maintaining and utilising internal test suites using Rspec, Qunit, PHPUnit, and Selenium testing frameworks.
- Integrating UI designs for the frontend from the design team, using JavaScript/jQuery/AngularJS and HTML/CSS.
- Designing and implementing RESTful APIs.

Construction Operative, Nyland Construction, August 2013 - August 2014

• A *temporary* position held after moving away from tech support and then securing a job as a software developer.

Linux Engineer, UKFast, January 2013 - August 2013

• Working as part of a large support team, supporting several thousands of Linux servers, clusters and complex bespoke solutions. Gained experience of supporting and administering Linux systems in a large hosting environment, supporting a wide and diverse range of customer solutions and requirements.

- Working with team leaders, tending to customer problems and providing solutions, whilst liaising with a range of departments within the business.
- Providing technical pre-sales advice, offering help and advice to account managers to maintain strong relationships with client base and working with data centre (NOC) engineers in disaster recovery situations.
- Assisting with the research and development of internal business systems, applications and services.

System Support Engineer, Kaleida, November 2009 - January 2013

- Telephone support for around 400 users (laptops/desktops/mobile devices) and 30 servers, both for Kaleida internally and also for their external client services.
- Asterisk VOIP Communications Server: Played a key role in the development, administration and support of a cloud based outbound dialler solution using Asterisk. Clients included: BMW, National Trust, NHS Direct and Marks and Spencer.
- Monitoring and supporting internal and client services and infrastructure, including telephony systems, email services, databases and applications.
- Database administration for Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL databases.

Education and Training

Microsoft Certifications

- · Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Certified Desktop Support Technician
- Microsoft Certified IT Professional (MCITP)
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS)
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate

Lymm High School 6th Form College, 2007 – 2009

- A2 in Design & Technology: Systems & Control
- A2 in Business Studies
- A2 in Biology
- AS in Chemistry

Lymm High School, 2001 – 2007

- 6 x GCSEs, grades A-C (Including Maths, English and Science)
- 1 x Btec completed to Distinction level (Construction)

Hobbies and Interests

- Maintains a personal website: <u>joenyland.me</u>.
- Tries to blog often about technology, development and hobbies: joenyland.me/blog.
- Works on projects in his spare time to refine skills and learn new technologies.
- Enjoys contributing to open source projects, helping out in discussion lists, participating in beta testing and debugging.
- Researches new and upcoming technologies and is constantly striving to expand on their knowledge and experience.
- Is a keen road and mountain cyclist, sea kayaker and also enjoys swimming.
- Has a passion for music and also enjoys reading in his spare time.

Additional Information

- Is a home owner and lives in Northwich, Cheshire, UK.
- Is willing to commute into Manchester, Liverpool or the surrounding areas.
- Holds a full clean UK driving licence and owns a car.

References and Sample Work

- References are available on request from all above employers.
- Please also refer to some sample work in my portfolio, which is available on my website: joenyland.me/portfolio.